<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xsl-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/module/module2html.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="../transforms/schemas/CCModule.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!-- </Package>  -->
<Module name="Voice/Video over IP (VVoIP)" boilerplate="yes" target-product="VVoIP" target-products="VVoIP Devices" xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:sec="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1/section">
  <PPReference>
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPVersion>2.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2026-03-17</PPPubDate>
      <Keywords>VVoIP</Keywords>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  <RevisionHistory>
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2020-10-28</date>
      <subject>Initial publication</subject>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <version>2.0</version>
      <date>2026-03-17</date>
      <subject>CC:2022 updates, incorporation of TDs</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <include-pkg id="ssh">
    <git>
      <url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/ssh</url>
      <branch>master</branch>
    </git>
    <url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/protectionprofiles/515</url>
  </include-pkg>
  <include-pkg id="tls">
    <git>
      <url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/tls</url>
      <branch>release-2.1</branch>
    </git>
    <url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/protectionprofiles/465</url>
    <depends on="fcs-eap-ext-1"/>
  </include-pkg>
  <include-pkg id="X509">
    <git>
      <url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/X509</url>
      <branch>master</branch>
    </git>
    <url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/protectionprofiles/511</url>
  </include-pkg>
  <include-pkg id="pkgVPNC">
    <git>
      <url>https://github.com/commoncriteria/vpnclient</url>
      <branch>release-3.0</branch>
    </git>
    <url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/protectionprofiles/487</url>
  </include-pkg>
  <pp-preferences/>
  <sec:Introduction>
    <sec:Overview title="Overview">
      The scope of this PP-Module is to describe the security functionality of a Voice/Video over IP (VVoIP)
      endpoint in terms of
      <xref g="CC"/>
      and to define functional and assurance requirements for such products. This PP-Module is intended for use with the following Base-PPs:
      f
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>Protection Profile for Application Software, Version 2.0</h:li>
        <h:li>Network Device collaborative Protection Profile, Version 4.0</h:li>
      </h:ul>
      <h:p>These Base-PPs are both valid because a VVoIP endpoint is a specific type of network device or software
        application that carries sensitive data over remote channels and uses protocols to do so that a typical
        network device or software application does not implement. Therefore, additional security requirements
        are necessary to ensure that sensitive communications are not subject to unauthorized disclosure to
        unintended recipients.</h:p>
      <h:p>Note that the NDcPP defines an optional architecture for a “distributed TOE” that allows for security
        functionality to be spread across multiple distinct components. However, a TOE that conforms to the
        NDcPP and this PP-Module will not be a distributed TOE. All security functionality will be contained within
        a single physical device.</h:p>
    </sec:Overview>
    <tech-terms>
      <suppress>Extended Package</suppress>
      <term full="Basic telephony functions">The basic functions a VVoIP phone must provide – pick up, dial tone, dial, talk.</term>
      <term full="Call control">The packets exchanged between devices to establish, maintain, and tear down a
      telephony call.</term>
      <term full="Client">A VVoIP endpoint.</term>
      <term full="Enterprise Session Controller" abbr="ESC">A VVoIP call control server for VVoIP devices.</term>
      <term full="H.323">A communications protocol defined by ITU-T that is used for creating, modifying, and
      terminating multimedia sessions with multiple participants.</term>
      <term full="Peer-to-Peer" abbr="P2P">A VVoIP architecture that forces each peer to be a server and client at the same time.</term>
      <term full="SDES-SRTP">A method of key negotiation for SRTP.</term>
      <term full="Session Initiation Protocol" abbr="SIP">A communications protocol defined by IETF that is used for creating, modifying, and
      terminating multimedia sessions with multiple participants.</term>
      <term full="Secure Real-Time Transport Protocol" abbr="SRTP">A protocol that is used to provide multimedia (voice/video) streaming services with
      added security of encryption, message authentication and integrity, and replay
      protection.</term>
      <term full="Sensitive Data">Call control/signal data, media data, and audit/management data that must be
      protected while in transit to prevent unauthorized disclosure.</term>
      <term full="Software/firmware update delivery channel">A trusted channel between a client and file server (which may be the same server as
      the call control server) for secure file download of software/firmware updates.</term>
      <term full="State">
        A configuration of a VVoIP endpoint based on how the user is currently using or not
      using the endpoint. Examples include:
        <h:ul>
          <h:li>Hook state: whether the endpoint is active (off-hook) or inactive (on-hook)</h:li>
          <h:li>Mute state: the endpoint is active but is deliberately not transmitting data</h:li>
          <h:li>Hold state: the endpoint is active but is deliberately not transmitting or
        receiving data</h:li>
        </h:ul>
      </term>
      <term full="Streaming media">The voice/video exchanged between VVoIP endpoints.</term>
      <term full="VVoIP Call Control Server">A VVoIP infrastructure device that performs call control functions between a client and
      other VVoIP endpoints; this may be either a dedicated device such as an ESC or a VVoIP
      device itself when using P2P.</term>
      <term full="Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol" abbr="DHCP"/>
      <term full="Internet Engineering Task Force" abbr="IETF"/>
      <term full="Internet Protocol" abbr="IP"/>
      <term full="International Telegraph Union – Telecommunication Standardization Sector" abbr="ITU-T"/>
      <term full="Network Time Protocol" abbr="NTP"/>
      <term full="Transmission Control Protocol" abbr="TCP"/>
      <term full="Trivial File Transfer Protocol" abbr="TFTP"/>
      <term full="User Datagram Protocol" abbr="UDP"/>
      <term full="Voice/Video over IP" abbr="VVoIP"/>
    </tech-terms>
    <sec:Compliant_Targets_of_Evaluation>
      <h:p>This PP-Module specifically addresses a dedicated network device or software application that facilitates
      the exchange of voice or video communication across an Internet Protocol (IP) network. The endpoint is
      a client (TOE) that communicates with a VVoIP call control server and may serve as its own call control
      server when using P2P. The VVoIP endpoint shall be able to secure file download from a file server to
      update VVoIP endpoint software and configuration, to establish secure communication for call control
      with the call control server, and to secure streaming media to other devices.</h:p>
      <h:p>The combination of the NDcPP and this PP-Module is a network device that provides VVoIP endpoint
      functionality in addition to all of the security functionality expected of a network device as mandated by
      the NDcPP. The combination of the App PP and this PP-Module is a software application running on a
      general-purpose operating system that includes VVoIP endpoint capabilities in addition to all of the
      security functionality expected of a software application as mandated by the App PP.</h:p>
      <h:p>This PP-Module describes the functional requirements and threats specific to the VVoIP endpoint. The
      most notable additions are requirements for the call control protocol (SIP, H.323) and streaming media
      protocol (SRTP, RTP). A conformant TOE is expected to be a standalone device or application; distributed
      TOE’s are not permitted.</h:p>
    </sec:Compliant_Targets_of_Evaluation>
    <sec:Use_Cases>
      <h:p>This PP-Module defines four potential use cases for the VVoIP TOE, defined below. The first two use cases
			define the physical embodiment of the TOE, while the latter two define its role in a telecommunications
			deployment.</h:p>
      <h:p>Regardless of the physical embodiment of the TOE, the expected functional capabilities are similar.
			However, when the TOE is deployed in a peer-to-peer architecture, it must perform auditing and call
			control functions that a client-server TOE does not need to perform because the Enterprise Session
			Controller provides those functions in that architecture. A client-server TOE may also perform its own
			auditing, but it is not required.</h:p>
      <usecases>
        <usecase title="Dedicated Appliance" id="usecase1">
          <description>The VVoIP endpoint is sold and packaged as a standalone network appliance that does not have
			a direct interface to the underlying platform operating system. In this use case, conformance to
			the NDcPP and this PP-Module is sufficient to ensure security. Note that the NDcPP defines
			optional functionality for “distributed TOEs” – for a TOE to conform to this PP-Module, it must be
			a single device and not a distributed TOE.</description>
        </usecase>
        <usecase title="Software Application" id="usecase2">
          <description>The VVoIP endpoint is sold and packaged as an application that is installed on a general-purpose
			computer or mobile device running a modifiable operating system (such as Windows or Linux).
			This computer may run end user applications above and beyond those used for VVoIP
			communications since it functions as a user workstation. In this case, the VVoIP endpoint
			application is expected to conform to both this PP-Module and the App PP.</description>
        </usecase>
        <usecase title="Client-Server Architecture" id="usecase3">
          <description>The VVoIP endpoint, whether hardware or software, is deployed in an environment where it
			interacts with an Enterprise Session Controller to facilitate call control functions.</description>
        </usecase>
        <usecase title="Peer-to-Peer Architecture" id="usecase4">
          <description>The VVoIP endpoint, whether hardware or software, is deployed in an environment where it
			interacts directly with other VVoIP endpoints without the use of an Enterprise Session Controller
			as an intermediary.</description>
        </usecase>
      </usecases>
    </sec:Use_Cases>
    <section title="Package Usage">
      This section contains selections and assignments that are required when the listed Functional Packages are claimed by this PP-Module.
      <h:br/>
      Package Usage guidance defined in the TOE's relevant Base-PP applies to the usage of the packages for this module, unless explicitly stated otherwise in this section.
      <package-usage-list>
        <package-usage ref="X509">
          <usage id="usage-x509-roles" title="Certificate Verification and Assertion Required in FIA_XCU_EXT.1.1">
            <description>Because this PP-Module mandates support for mutual authentication for media channels, the ST author shall select the options to both verify and assert certificate identities in FIA_XCU_EXT.1.1.</description>
            <config>
              <ref-id>dummy-ref-id</ref-id>
            </config>
          </usage>
          <usage id="usage-x509-revocation-sigalgs" title="Limitations on Signature Algorithms in FIA_X509_EXT.1.1">
            <description>The TOE must utilize appropriate cryptographic algorithms that conform to CNSA standards. Thus, the TOE shall utilize no other algorithms outside of those specified in RFC 8603 for certificate or CRL signatures. 
              Additionally, the TOE shall not use ECDSA with SHA-512 signatures for OCSP responses, and shall utilize no other algorithms for OCSP responses.</description>
            <config>
              <ref-id>dummy-ref-id</ref-id>
            </config>
          </usage>
          <usage id="usage-x509-extensions" title="Required Extension Processing for FIA_X509_EXT.1.2">
            <description>The ST author shall select the options to process the basicConstraints and extendedKeyUsage extensions. Other extensions may be selected as appropriate without restriction.</description>
            <config>
              <ref-id>dummy-ref-id</ref-id>
            </config>
          </usage>
          <usage id="usage-x509-revocation-methods" title="CRL or OCSP-based Revocation Required for FIA_X509_EXT.1.3 ">
            <description>The TOE must support revocation that only involves CRL or OCSP. Accordingly, the TOE shall select only from options involving CRL or OCSP in FIA_X509_EXT.1.3 (e.g., the selection to treat all certificates older than a given short timeframe is not an acceptable substitute or alternative for supporting CRL or OCSP).</description>
            <config>
              <ref-id>dummy-ref-id</ref-id>
            </config>
          </usage>
          <usage id="usage-x509-revocation-connections" title="Connections to CRL or OCSP Servers Required for FIA_X509_EXT.1.4">
            <description>Because the TOE is required to support CRL or OCSP, the TSF shall support an appropriate mechanism for obtaining revocation status information. In the case of CRL, the ST author shall claim that revocation status information is obtained via network connection to a CRL distribution point. In the case of OCSP, the ST author shall claim that revocation status information is obtained via network connection to an OCSP responder, via OCSP stapling, or via OCSP multi-stapling.</description>
            <config>
              <ref-id>dummy-ref-id</ref-id>
            </config>
          </usage>
          <usage id="usage-x509-eku-values" title="Restrictions on Acceptable Key Usage Values for FIA_X509_EXT.1.5">
            <description>The TOE will always support the use of extendedKeyUsage values to verify that X.509 certificates are used in accordance with their intended purpose. Accordingly, the ST author shall claim that the TOE supports the processing of extendedKeyUsage fields in the leaf certificate (as opposed to application of trust store context rules or passing the certification path or other supported context information to an external function) and shall select all values that are relevant to the claimed uses of X.509 in the ST. In particular, since the PP does not define any functions that require the use of S/MIME, the ST author shall not select this as an extendedKeyUsage value to be validated.</description>
            <config>
              <ref-id>dummy-ref-id</ref-id>
            </config>
          </usage>
          <usage id="usage-x509-functions" title="Requirements on Functions for FIA_X509_EXT.2.1">
            <description>The ST author shall additionally ensure that the selections and assignments in this requirement reflect the TOE's usage of X.509 certificate validation for TLS. Other assignments and selections may be made as applicable for other TOE functions.</description>
            <config>
              <ref-id>dummy-ref-id</ref-id>
            </config>
          </usage>
        </package-usage>
        <package-usage ref="tls">
          <usage id="usage-tls-roles" title="DTLS or TLS Server and Client Functionality Required">
            <description>The ST author shall select the option to utilize TLS as a client. The ST author shall additionally select the option to utilize DTLS as a client if support for DTLS is claimed in FTP_ITC.1.</description>
            <config>
              <ref-id>dummy-ref-id</ref-id>
            </config>
          </usage>
          <usage id="usage-tls-mutual-auth" title="DTLS or TLS Mutual Authentication Required">
            <description>The ST shall select the option to support mutual authentication in FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 and FCS_TLSS_EXT.1, or FCS_DTLSC_EXT.1 and FCS_DTLSS_EXT.1, according with the protocol support claimed in FTP_ITC.1.</description>
            <config>
              <ref-id>dummy-ref-id</ref-id>
            </config>
          </usage>
        </package-usage>
      </package-usage-list>
    </section>
    <section title="Implementation-Based Features" id="sec-features">
      The following features of the TOE are implementation-based. A TOE is not required to implement these features to conform to this PP-Module, but if the feature is implemented, it is expected that associated implementation-based requirements are claimed as part of the TSF.
      <implements>
        <feature id="feat-swapp" title="Software Application with Logging">
          <description>The TOE is a software application and claims the App-PP as the Base-PP. The TOE additionally implements logging features (i.e. includes one or more of the following SFRs in the ST: 
		  FAU_GEN.1/CSADMIN, FAU_GEN.1/CSVVOIP, FAU_GEN.1/P2PADMIN, FAU_GEN.1/P2PVVOIP).</description>
        </feature>
      </implements>
    </section>
  </sec:Introduction>
  <sec:Conformance_Claims>
    <CClaimsInfo cc-version="cc-2022r1" cc-approach="direct-rationale">
      <cc-st-conf>exact</cc-st-conf>
      <cc-pt2-conf>extended</cc-pt2-conf>
      <cc-pt3-conf>extended</cc-pt3-conf>
      <cc-pp-conf/>
      <cc-pp-config-with>
        <PP-cc-ref>Network Device collaborative Protection Profile Version 4.0</PP-cc-ref>
        <PP-cc-ref>Protection Profile for Application Software Version 2.0</PP-cc-ref>
      </cc-pp-config-with>
      <cc-pkg-claim>
        <FP-cc-ref conf="conformant">Functional Package for TLS, version 2.0</FP-cc-ref>
      </cc-pkg-claim>
    </CClaimsInfo>
  </sec:Conformance_Claims>
  <!-- 3.0 Security Problem Definition-->
  <sec:Security_Problem_Definition>
    <h:p>The security problem is described in terms of the threats that the TOE is expected to address, assumptions
	about its operational environment, and any organizational security policies that the TOE is expected to
	enforce.</h:p>
    <!-- 3.1 Threats -->
    <sec:Threats>
      The following threats defined in this PP-Module extend the threats defined by the Base-PP.
      <threats>
        <threat name="T.MEDIA_DISCLOSURE">
          <description>An attacker can use the encrypted variable rate vocoder frames to their advantage to decode
			transmitted data. An attacker can also use improperly protected data to discern sensitive information.</description>
          <!-- New mapping to build updated threat mapping table. -->
          <addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 (from <xref to="TLS"/>)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates the threat by defining the TLS client implementation used to secure call control and streaming media channels used for VVoIP.</rationale>
          <addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 (from <xref to="TLS"/>)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates the threat by defining the TOE’s implementation of mutual authentication for its TLS client</rationale>
          <addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.1 (from <xref to="X509"/>)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates the threat by defining requirements for the use of X.509 certificates that TLS functionality depends on.</rationale>
          <addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.2 (from <xref to="X509"/>)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates the threat by defining requirements for the use of X.509 certificates that TLS functionality depends on.</rationale>
          <addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.3 (from <xref to="X509"/>)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>Mitigates the threat by defining requirements for the use of X.509 certificates that TLS functionality depends on.</rationale>
        </threat>
        <threat name="T.UNDETECTED_TRANSMISSION">
          <description>An attacker may cause the TOE to exfiltrate audio or video media over a remote channel while in a
			state where the user has a reasonable expectation that no media is being transmitted.</description>
          <!-- New mapping to build updated threat mapping table. -->
        </threat>
      </threats>
    </sec:Threats>
    <!-- 3.2 Assumptions -->
    <sec:Assumptions>
      <h:p>The following assumptions that are defined in this PP-Module extend the assumptions that are defined
		by the Base-PPs.</h:p>
      <assumptions>
        <assumption name="A.UPDATE_SOURCE">
          <description>
            It is assumed that TOE software/firmware updates will be made available on either the call control
			server that the TOE connects to or a separate file server managed by the organization.
            <h:p/>
            Note that because this PP-Module specifically disallows distributed TOEs, a conformant TOE will not claim
			A.COMPONENTS_RUNNING when NDcPP is the Base-PP.
          </description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.UPDATE_SOURCE">
            <rationale>The objective satisfies the assumption
			by ensuring that TOE updates are
			made available in the intended location.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
    </sec:Assumptions>
    <!-- 3.3 Organizational Security Policies -->
    <sec:Organizational_Security_Policies>
      <OSPs/>
    </sec:Organizational_Security_Policies>
  </sec:Security_Problem_Definition>
  <!-- 4.0 Security Objectives -->
  <sec:Security_Objectives>
    <!-- 4.1 Security Objectives for the TOE -->
    <!-- 4.2 Security Objctives for the Operational Environment -->
    <sec:Security_Objectives_for_the_Operational_Environment>
      <h:p>The following environmental security objectives that are defined in this PP-Module extend the objectives
		that are defined by the Base-PPs.</h:p>
      <SOEs>
        <SOE name="OE.UPDATE_SOURCE">
          <description>
            <h:p>The operational environment will have TOE software/firmware made available on either the call
        		control server that the TOE connects to or a separate file server managed by the organization.</h:p>
            <h:p>Note that because this PP-Module specifically disallows distributed TOEs, a conformant TOE will not claim
				OE.COMPONENTS_RUNNING when NDcPP is the Base-PP.</h:p>
          </description>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs>
    </sec:Security_Objectives_for_the_Operational_Environment>
    <!-- 4.3 Security Objectives Rationale -->
    <sec:Security_Objectives_Rationale/>
  </sec:Security_Objectives>
  <!-- 5.0 Security Requirements -->
  <sec:Security_Requirements title="Security Requirements">
    <!-- 5.1 TOE Security Functional Requirements -->
    <man-sfrs/>
    <opt-sfrs/>
    <sel-sfrs/>
    <obj-sfrs/>
    <impl-dep-sfrs/>
  </sec:Security_Requirements>
  <appendix title="Implicitly Satisfied Requirements" id="implicit-reqs">
    <h:p>
      This appendix lists requirements that should be considered satisfied by products successfully evaluated
			against this PP-Module. However, these requirements are not featured explicitly as SFRs and should not
			be included in the ST. They are not included as standalone SFRs because it would increase the time, cost,
			and complexity of evaluation. This approach is permitted by [CC] Part 1, 8.2 Dependencies between
			components.
      <h:p/>
      This information benefits systems engineering activities which call for inclusion of particular security
			controls. Evaluation against the PP-Module provides evidence that these controls are present and have
			been evaluated.
    </h:p>
    <h:table>
      <h:tr class="header">
        <h:td>Requirement</h:td>
        <h:td>Rationale for Satisfaction</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FAU_GEN.2 – User identity association</h:td>
        <h:td>The iterations of FAU_GEN.1.2 explicitly requires that the OS
					record any user account associated with each event; therefore,
					it is duplicative to include a separate requirement to associate a
					user account with each event.
					If the TOE claims conformance to the NDcPP, the dependency is
					explicitly met through FAU_GEN.2.</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FIA_UID.1 – Timing of Identification</h:td>
        <h:td>
          <h:p>
            For the purpose of logging and processing VVoIP telephony
					functions, the TOE is identified solely by underlying system or
					configuration characteristics (e.g., IP address, phone number)
					independent of the identity of the user interacting with the
					TOE.
            <h:p/>
            When the TOE is a software application, neither this PP-Module
					nor the Base-PP (App PP) define a separate identification and
					authentication mechanism for the software application to
					interact with its management interface. The software
					application assumes that accessing the OS platform itself is
					sufficient to grant access to the application. For accountability
					purposes, the user of the TOE is identified as the user that
					logged in to the OS platform and subsequently interacted with
					the TSF.
          </h:p>
        </h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FMT_MSA.1 – Management of Security Attributes</h:td>
        <h:td>
          <h:p>
            This SFR defines the TOE security attributes that can be
					managed and what management role can administer them.
					Specifically, this is indirectly dependent on FDP_IFF.1. The PP-Module defines two iterations of FDP_IFF.1. Each of these
					iterations define explicit rules that determine when the TSF
					transmits call control and media data.
            <h:p/>
            The relevant attributes are either directly under the control of
					an ordinary user, such that no specific security authorization is
					needed, or they are entirely under the control of the TSF and
					cannot be influenced by the user regardless of privilege. An
					example of the first case in that in FDP_IFF.1.2, whether or not
					the TOE is in the off-hook state or the mute state is
					controllable by a user with physical access to the TOE and does 
					not require the assumption of an administrative role. An
					example of the second case is in FDP_IFF.1.2/CallControl,
					where the TSF will determine if the other end of the
					connection is a valid VVoIP endpoint, which is something the
					user has no ability to configure or influence.
          </h:p>
        </h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FMT_MSA.3 – Static Attribute Initialization</h:td>
        <h:td>
          <h:p>
            This SFR is a dependency on FDP_IFF.1. The PP-Module defines
					two iterations of FDP_IFF.1. Each of these iterations define
					explicit rules that determine when the TSF transmits call
					control and media data. FMT_MSA.3 has not been specified
					because the default state of the attributes used to determine if
					data flow is authorized is not relevant to enforcement of the
					rules.
            <h:p/>
            For example, FDP_IFF.1.2 states that the TSF will not transmit
					media data within a call if the TOE is in the mute state.
					Whether the call starts with the mute state active or inactive
					does not affect the enforcement of the rule, and requiring the
					ST to state this information does not affect the security of the
					TSF.
          </h:p>
        </h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FMT_SMR.1 – Security Roles</h:td>
        <h:td>
          <h:p>
            When the TOE is a software application, neither this PP-Module
					nor the Base-PP (App PP) define security roles that are
					authorized to perform management functionality on the TSF.
					For user access, the TOE does not require separate
					authentication to the TSF because authentication to the OS
					platform on which the TOE is installed is sufficient user access
					control; a user logged in to the OS platform is assumed to be a
					valid user of the TOE.
            <h:p/>
            If the TOE is registered to an ESC, the ESC may be able to issue
					management commands to the TOE. No separate ‘user role’ is
					needed to define this because the ESC is not a ‘user’ and so
					FMT_SMR.1.2 is not applicable in this context. The ESC’s
					authorization to manage the TSF is implicitly granted through
					the user registering the TOE to the ESC.
          </h:p>
        </h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FPT_STM.1 – Reliable time stamps</h:td>
        <h:td>
          <h:p>
            The iterations of FAU_GEN.1.2 explicitly requires that the
					software application TSF associate timestamps with audit
					records; therefore it is duplicative to include a separate
					timestamp requirement. Additionally, the App PP has an
					assumption of relying upon a trustworthy computing platform
					with a reliable time clock for its execution, so the dependency is
					also met through the assumption.
            <h:p/>
            Alternatively, if the TOE is registered to an ESC, the selection-based requirement FPT_STM_EXT.1/VVoIP must be claimed,
					which is sufficient to address the dependency as the TSF will
					receive time data from the operational environment that is
					assumed to be reliable.
            <h:p/>
            If the TOE claims conformance to the NDcPP, the dependency is
					also explicitly met through FPT_STM_EXT.1, regardless of whether the TOE is deployed in a client-server configuration
					(with registration to an ESC) or peer-to-peer configuration (with
					no ESC involved).
          </h:p>
        </h:td>
      </h:tr>
    </h:table>
  </appendix>
  <appendix title="Entropy Documentation and Assessment" id="entropyappendix">
    <h:p>The TOE does not require any additional supplementary information to describe its entropy sources
			beyond the requirements outlined in the Base-PPs. As with other Base-PP requirements, the only
			additional requirement is that the entropy documentation also applies to the specific VVoIP capabilities
			of the TOE that require random data, in addition to any functionality required by the claimed Base-PP.</h:p>
  </appendix>
  <bibliography>
    <entry id="bibAppPP">
      <tag>AppPP</tag>
      <description>
        <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/protectionprofiles/516">Protection Profile for Application Software, Version 2.0, June 16, 2025</h:a>
      </description>
    </entry>
    <entry id="bibNDcPP">
      <tag>NDcPP</tag>
      <description>
        <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/protectionprofiles/524">collaborative Protection Profile for Network Devices, Version 4.0, December 22, 2025</h:a>
      </description>
    </entry>
  </bibliography>
</Module>
